Finding Aid for Ann Heler Papers, 1993-1998
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ann Heler papers 1993-1998
Heler, Ann
0.5 linear feet and 1 oversize folder
2011064 Aa 2; UAm
Papers of Ann Heler, a resident of Ferndale, Mich., who was a leader of the gay and lesbian community. Heler also participated in the Gay Games, a cultural event for the purpose of unity and identity within the national and international gay and lesbian community.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Ann Heler (donor no. 10513 ) in 2011.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Ann Heler was a resident of Ferndale, Mich. and an active member of the gay and lesbian community. In the early 1990's Heler organized FANs "Friends and Neighbors", to protect the rights of the gay and lesbian population in Ferndale Michigan. As the city became a more tolerant place for the community to live, FANs disbanded about 10 years after they began. Heler later joined Team Great Lakes, participating in Gay Games IV in 1994. The Gay Games began in 1982 as a cultural event for the purpose of unity and identity within the national and international gay and lesbian community.
The collection largely documents Ann Heler's involvement in the Gay Games during the 1990's. The emphasis of these sporting events was to help the Gay and Lesbian Community establish a global unity and strengthen their identity. The Papers of Ann Heler are arranged into two series: Personal Records, and Other Materials, and one outsize folder.
Subjects:
Heler, Ann.; Gay Games.; Gays and sports.; Lesbians--Michigan--Ferndale.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Videotapes.
- Personal Records
  - Human Rights Campaign Fund Dinner, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Photojournal of Gay Games III and Cultural Festival entitled "The Spirit Captured" 1990 (Box 1)
  - Photojournal of Gay Games IV and Stonewall entitled "Unity" 1994 (Box 1)
  - Team Great Lakes
    - Ephemera -- Poster and Pin for Gay Games 1994 (Box 1)
      (see also oversize folder)
    - Flyers and other mailings, correspondence, lists of members, and similar records (Box 1)
    - Photograph of people with posters assembled in front of public building; also photograph of outdoor information booth (Box 1)
- Other Materials
  - GLBT magazines with some content on the Gay Games (Box 1)
  - Newspapers and Clippings (Box 1)
  - Videotapes, VHS
    - Compilation of three segments regarding the Gay Games, undated, ca. 15 min. (Box 1)
    - "Dog Gone Proud: Story of the Grand Rapids Front Runners" undated (Box 1)
    - "Gay Games IV/Stonewall 25" 1994 Network Q: Television for Gay America (Box 1)
    - Promotional video entitled "Spirit of the Games" 1993, ca. 5 min. (Box 1)
  - Poster (Folder 1)
  - FANs of Ferndale metal street sign
Related Material
The library also has the papers of Dewey Ames, an organizer of the Gay Games.